Bruno Baère Pederassi Lomba de Araujo

mail: bruno.baere@gmail.com phone: +5521996826336

SUMMARY

I am motivated by challenging tasks and to teach others about what I have learned. My experience as both an academic researcher and as a systems analyst helps me to approach, to model, to understand problems, and to develop a solution. My analytical skills have been proven useful in detecting and preventing bugs and problems in systems modeling.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Computer Graphics

2010 - 2012

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro - PUC-Rio

Advisor: Bruno Feijó

Dissertation title: A study on dynamic difficulty adaptivity for games

Granted 2 years of CAPES scholarship

GPA/CR: 3.54 / 89%

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering

2005 - 2009

Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio de Janeiro - PUC-Rio

Minor: Advanced studies in Mathematics

Final project title: A shade tree editor for OGRE materials

Granted 2 years of CNPQ scholarship

Language proficiency: Cambridge English FCE grade B2

2003

EXPERIENCE

Product Owner

Feb 2018 - Present

Instituto Tecgraf - PUC-Rio, Computational Geophysics - v3o2 Project

Product Owner in v3o2 project. Responsible for the product value of Seismic Tie, Well Log Viewer, and Image Log Segmentation modules of the v3o2 application.

Senior Systems Analyst / Researcher

Aug 2011 - Feb 2018

Instituto Tecgraf - PUC-Rio, Computational Geophysics - v3o2 Project

Worked in v3o2 project, a seismic data visualizer for Petrobras, as C++ developer, and Scrum Master.

- Programmed various parts of the application, using OpenGL, GTK+, and boost.
- Presented with colleagues a 2 day workshop on Scrum for team members.
- Testing and QA using GoogleTest framework, valgrind, and cppcheck.
- Promoted and maintained the system for the upgrade to RedHat 6.
- Documentation of the development environment setup.

Researcher

Apr 2009 - Aug 2011

ICAD/Visionlab - PUC-Rio

Researcher in games, digital entertainment and simulations. C# programmer in a joint project with CENPES and USP. Developed a shade tree editor in C# for building DirectX shaders for the proof tank visualizer project.

Undergraduate teaching assistant

Mar 2009 - Dec 2009

Department of Computer Science - PUC-Rio

Worked as UTA for Introduction to Programming (C language) and Data Structures. Gave extra classes at Saturdays and post-class hours, resolving exercises and exams.

Intern Oct 2008 - Mar 2009

ICA - Laboratório de Inteligência Computacional Aplicada – PUC-Rio

C# developer. Worked at FxANEEL project, developing part of the user interface with WindowsForms and XML database access. Developed a wrapper for GSLIB library in C# and created the model for library documentation used by the lab.

Scientific Initiation

Aug 2006 - Aug 2008

ICAD/Visionlab - PUC-Rio

Development of a simulation library for Torque Game Engine. Researched game engine use in fluid simulations, programmed in C++ using OGRE rendering engine. Granted 2 years of CNPQ scholarship.

PUBLICATIONS

Maria das G. de A. Chagas, **Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo**, Waldecir V. Faria, Cezar G. Loureiro, Maria I. M. M. Carmo, Nelson J. Donato, Tathiana S. T. Silva, Victoria D. Maidantchik, Yann L. M. de M. Marques. *Design de Jogos de RPG Digitais: Uma investigação sobre a experiência de jogo*. In: Proceedings of XIV Brazilian Symposium on Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2015), Teresina, Piauí, Brazil, November 2015.

Paula C. Ribeiro, **Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo**, Alberto Raposo. *ComFiM: A Cooperative Serious Game to Encourage the Development of Communicative Skills between Children with Autism.* In: Proceedings of the XIII Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2014), Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil, November 2014. DOI: 10.1109/SBGAMES.2014.19

Bruno B. P. L. de Araujo, Bruno Feijó. *Evaluating dynamic difficulty adaptivity in shoot'em up games*. In: Proceedings of the XII Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames 2013), São Paulo, Brazil, October 2013.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR COURSES

Fundamentals of Project Planning and Management University of Virginia on Coursera, 8h.

2018

O setor de games no Brasil: panorama, carreiras e oportunidades Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, 30h.

2018

Introduction to User Experience Design

2017

Georgia Institute of Technology on Coursera, 10h. Certificate V8K283SJ8Q9T.

Gamification 2016

University of Pennsylvania on Coursera, 48h. Certificate WEVTGH9S3WK5.

A complexidade sensível: Um paralelo entre videogames e arte 2016 Universidade Estadual de Campinas on Coursera, 14h. Certificate EC8XZEZZ26HY.

Oil & Gas Industry Operations and Markets

Duke University on Coursera, 10h. Certificate WEVTGH9S3WK5.

Petroleum geology for non-geologists 2014 ABGP - The Brazilian Association of Petroleum Geologists, 20h. COMPUTER SKILLS Languages: C, C++, C#, Lua.

CERTIFICATIONS Certified Scrum Product Owner

Certifier: Scrum Alliance License: 000304959

Certified Scrum Master Valid: Jan 2014 - Mar 2020

Certifier: Scrum Alliance License: 000304959

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES Co-organizer of PUC-Rio's Global Game Jam Helped organize PUC-Rio's Global Game Jam.

Volunteer reviewer for Entertainment Computing 2016 - Present Volunteer reviewer for Entertainment Computing, an Elsevier journal. ISSN 1875-

9521.

Researcher at PUC-Rio's Game Design Research Group

2013 - Present

Valid: Mar 2014 - Mar 2020

Associate researcher in the Arts & Design Department research group under prof. Maria das Graças Chagas advisory. Themes include player-NPC relationship and

artificial intelligence.

SBGames 2011's Independent Games Festival contestant

2011

Jan 2018

Contestant with the game Lights Out. Awarded with the third place in people's choice in the Art Game cathegory.

https://sites.google.com/site/bbaere/projetos-1/lights

GAMES

Lights Out

2011

A puzzle-like art game for 2 players made in GameMaker 8.1. Presented at SBGames 2011, FILE Games 2012, Festival Games Brasil 2013. Role: programmer (GameMaker Scripting Language) and 2D artist.

Seu Espião Safado!

2011

A print-and-play dice game for 3 players where 2 agents are trying to uncover a spy's secret (Brazilian Portuguese only). Role: game designer.

You Are Trash! 2009

A Java 2D game mix of puzzle and platformer, made in the Gamerama project. Role:

programmer and game designer.

OTHER INFORMATION

Personal homepage: http://killerasus.github.io

GitHub: https://github.com/killerasus

Lattes curriculum: http://lattes.cnpg.br/0738342776987656